application use cases on layer one also
managing block rots and and state roots
and proof systems for layer twos layer
one is the thing that secures layer 2os
cross layer two operations um and layer
one needs to still be powerful enough to
handle cross um a lot of things
happening especially in the case where a
layer two fails the difference between a
layer two and an independent chain is
that even if your warer 2 gets 51%
attacked or 91% attacked or the team
shots down layer one is still stands
there to protect the users users are
able to prove their whole their assets
and their ownership and their state
inside of the layer two and migrated
down back down to layer one in order for
this to actually be possible layer one
needs to actually be powerful enough to
handle the load if a layer two actually
does fail recently there was a live
experiment of this uh so dyd DX V3 I
believe shut down recently and the uh L2
beat people actually wrote their own
implementation of escape hatch software
and so without any involvement from the
dydx team uh users are able to take any
assets that they have ins um inside of D
ydx V3 and bring it back down to the
ethereum L1
so layer twos are not just multi the
ability to Mo move your assets out of
the layer two and back to layer one if
the layer 2 fails without the layer two
teams involvement is not just Theory it
is
reality
so okay L1 runs some applications and L1
protects the l2s what do the l2s do l2s
provide speed and scale so on the left
here you have a chart of like basically
the same as the chart that Josh showed
earlier basically Layer Two fees and
this is just what they've done this year
so this year Layer Two fees have gone
down from about 50 cents to less than 1
cent so this is a massive change right
this basically means that for an
incredibly wide class of applications
ethereum has overnight gone from
being basically unaffordable to being
completely affordable so that's fees
[Applause]
now transaction inclusion times right so
who here remembers the experience of
sending a transaction and then having to
wait some arbitrary number of minutes
could be 10 could be 40 could be 90 for
the transaction to get
included who here remembers having this
experience in
ethereum who here remembers having this
experience in ethereum in the past 6
months so ethereum has improved
massively now this is actually a pretty
linear progression that we've had all
the way since the beginning right so
Bitcoin 10minute block times and uh
Bitcoin has uh this uh thing called A
Plus un distribution that of course
ethereum also had um had during the
proof of work era but then we decided we
don't like fish and so we switched to
proof of steak
so Bitcoin average walk time 10 minutes
often you have to wait up to 1 hour now
in in ethereum uh the average block time
is 12 seconds but then there's still
this like annoying phenomenon where if
you send a transaction and you get
unlucky with the gas price that you set
maybe you would have to wait like 10
minutes or 20 minutes accidentally EIP
1559 which came in 2021 basically solved
that and created a situation where
you're able to reliably send a
transaction and expect to see it
included usually within one block and
then the merge because of this
interesting Quirk of mathematics
even though the average time between
blocks reduced only from 13 seconds to
12 seconds the average time between you
sending a transaction and your and your
transaction getting included in a block
reduced from a little bit more than 13
seconds to a little bit more than six
seconds um so math problem figure out
why this is true it's actually a really
fun fact so post merge basically goes
down to like about 6 to 30 seconds and
then finally with layer twos you have
preon
and you have layer twos that are fast
enough to just confirm your transaction
within a couple hundred
milliseconds so layer twos provide speed
layer twos provide scale and the way
that you as a user see scale is you get
to be part of an application where lots
and lots of things are happening and at
the same time your transaction fees get
to continue to be
cheap so history of ethereum right so
November 2013 the white paper July 2015
the launch around 2018 that was the time
when ethereum settled on it's
approximate design for proof of stake
and data availability sampling so the
original papers and like documents for
data availability sampling and aaser
coding um I wrote those back in 2017 and
then we settled on uh the Casper the
Friendly finality Gadget also at the end
of
2017 actually if you really want and you
can dig I think it's like either GitHub
ethereum research or like GitHub
ethereum simple Casper you just like
search for the directory called Simple
Casper and you can find like contracts
written in serpent like who here
remember
serpent okay who here uses serpent good
I mean I mean I think like I think
python is uh like is really beautiful
but I think if you uh like if you want
that then you should code in Viper Viper
is actually like great it's actually
kept improving quite a bit for the last
couple of years so we had basically yeah
okay yay glad for Viper um
okay and so in 2017 actually we
attempted to like basically do this like
full like abstraction thing and even
write the proof of stake logic directly
as a smart contract and so there's this
like really fun demo that we launched at
I think it was actually like 2320